<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>uKnit User Guide - CodeTab on Codetab</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/</link><description>Recent content in uKnit User Guide - CodeTab on Codetab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>uKnit - CodeTab</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/introduction/</guid><description>uKnit I love unit tests but hate the process of writing them. Every Java developer knows the dull routine: look at the code in the source editor, toggle to the test code editor, create or copy variables, initialize, write assertions, and repeat the mind-numbing chore hundreds of times more. To complete a single test case, you have to toggle dozens of times and make equal or even more cuts and pastes.</description></item><item><title>uKnit - CodeTab</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/quickstart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/quickstart/</guid><description>uKnit Quickstart The preferred way to use uKnit in your project is to add it as a dependency in project&amp;rsquo;s pom.xml. We explain this with uknit-quickstart example and you can use uKnit in your project in the same way.
uKnit is also distributed as release zip which contains uKnit core and a Quickstart example projects. For whatever reason, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to add uknit dependency to your project&amp;rsquo;s pom then you have to install uKnit from the release zip.</description></item><item><title>uKnit - CodeTab</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/configuration/</guid><description>Configuration uKnit is configured through uknit/resources/uknit.properites. The complete set of configurable properties, with default values, are defined in uknit-defaults.properties and users are need to know few of them and reconfigure them in uknit/uknit.properties.
Source Paths The source class file is configured with following properties,
Property Description uknit.source.base Absolute path to the base of your project/module in IDE. Some examples are /orange/data/eclipse-workspace/scoopi-scraper, /home/m/IdeaProjects/playproject/workmodule. Note that in eclipse is path to your project and in IntelliJ it path to your module uknit.</description></item><item><title>uKnit - CodeTab</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/faq/</guid><description>1. Is there is any uKnit plugin for Eclipse or IntelliJ? Configuration involved to generate the test class is trivial, and once basic setup is done only uknit.source.class needs change; plugin is overkill. Then again based on acceptance of uKnit by the developers we may plan to release plugins in future.
2. Is tests generated by uKnit are accurate and complete? The objective of uKnit project is to assist developers by reducing coding and typing a test class.</description></item><item><title>uKnit - CodeTab</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/install/</guid><description>Install uKnit The preferred and the easier way to use uKnit is to add it as dependency in your project pom as explained in Quickstart.
uKnit is also distributed as release zip which contains uKnit core and a Quickstart example project. The uKnit core is a Maven project which needs to be in your IDE workspace along with the project for which you wish to generate unit tests. Install uKnit only if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to add uKnit dependency to your project&amp;rsquo;s pom for some reason.</description></item><item><title>uKnit - CodeTab</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/quickstart-gradle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.codetab.org/guide/uknit/quickstart-gradle/</guid><description>uKnit Quickstart with Gradle The preferred way to use uKnit in your project is to add it as a dependency in project&amp;rsquo;s build.gradle file. We explain this with uknit-quickstart example, and you can use uKnit in your project in the same way.
uKnit is also distributed as release zip which contains uKnit core and a Quickstart example projects. For whatever reason, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to add uknit dependency to your project&amp;rsquo;s build.</description></item></channel></rss>