<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>multiple tasks on Codetab</title>
    <link>https://www.codetab.org/tags/multiple-tasks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in multiple tasks on Codetab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 03:54:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.codetab.org/tags/multiple-tasks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Tasks - Scoopi Web Scraper - CodeTab</title>
      <link>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper-v094/multiple-tasks-v094/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 03:54:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper-v094/multiple-tasks-v094/</guid>
      <description>Multiple Tasks Scoopi can execute multiple tasks for a locator and also multiple tasks on multiple locatorGroups.
Multiple tasks and single Locator group The Example-1 scrape Price data from acme-quote.html page while Example-2 extracts Snapshot data from the same page. One option is to define acme-quote.html locator in two locatorGroups and assign task to each of them. This unnecessarily downloads acme-quote.html twice. Instead, it is better to define single locatorGroup and assign two tasks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi Tasks - Scoopi Web Scraper - why just scrape when you can scoop</title>
      <link>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper/advanced/multi-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 23:51:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper/advanced/multi-tasks/</guid>
      <description>Multiple Tasks Scoopi can execute multiple tasks for a locator and also multiple tasks on multiple locatorGroups.
Multiple tasks and single Locator group The Example-1 from fin folder scrape Price data from acme-snapshot.html page while Example-2 extracts Snapshot data from the same page. One option is to define acme-snapshot.html locator in two locatorGroups and assign task to each of them. This unnecessarily downloads acme-snapshot.html twice. Instead, it is better to define single locatorGroup and assign two tasks - priceTask and snapshotTask so that page downloads only once.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>