<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>persistence on Codetab</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/tags/persistence/</link><description>Recent content in persistence on Codetab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 01:02:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.codetab.org/tags/persistence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Persistence - Gotz ETL - CodeTab</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/gotz-etl/persistence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 21:10:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/gotz-etl/persistence/</guid><description>With persistence, Gotz offers following benefits.
reduce network usage as it can reuse the downloaded pages recover from the aborted run without redoing the tasks already completed avoid expensive parse operation as it can reuse the persisted data set expiry date for each page If you installed Gotz from GitHub, then to run examples with persistence we need to setup database. We explain how to install and setup HSQLDB as it is the easy one.</description></item><item><title>Persistence - Scoopi Web Scraper - CodeTab</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper-v094/persistence-v094/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 04:11:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper-v094/persistence-v094/</guid><description>Persistence With persistence, Scoopi offers following benefits.
reduce network usage as it can reuse the downloaded pages recover from the aborted run without redoing the tasks already completed avoid expensive parse operation as it can reuse the persisted data set expiry date for each page Setup Database If you running Scoopi from docker image then no database setup is required as docker image contains pre-configured MariaDB container. Please refer Scoopi with MariaDB to run Scoopi with MariaDB using docker-compose.</description></item><item><title>Persistence - Scoopi Web Scraper - why just scrape when you can scoop</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper/manage/persistence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 01:02:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper/manage/persistence/</guid><description>Persistence With persistence, Scoopi offers following benefits.
reduce network usage by reusing the downloaded pages recover from the aborted run by skipping the tasks already completed avoid expensive parse operation by reuse of persisted data set expiry date for each page Enable Persistence By default persistence is disabled in Scoopi through configuration setting scoopi.datastore.enable=false in conf/scoopi.properties file. To enable persistence, either set the property scoopi.datastore.enable=true or hash it out. By default, the scoopi objects are persisted in data/ directory and it is configurable through scoopi.</description></item><item><title>Persistence - Scoopi Web Scraper - why just scrape when you can scoop</title><link>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper-v097/manage/persistence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 01:02:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper-v097/manage/persistence/</guid><description>Persistence With persistence, Scoopi offers following benefits.
reduce network usage by reusing the downloaded pages recover from the aborted run by skipping the tasks already completed avoid expensive parse operation by reuse of persisted data set expiry date for each page Setup Database If you running Scoopi from docker image then no database setup is required as docker image contains pre-configured MariaDB container. Please refer Scoopi Installation to run Scoopi with MariaDB using docker-compose.</description></item></channel></rss>