<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>split definitions on Codetab</title>
    <link>https://www.codetab.org/tags/split-definitions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in split definitions on Codetab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 04:46:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.codetab.org/tags/split-definitions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Split Definitions - Gotz ETL - CodeTab</title>
      <link>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/gotz-etl/split-definitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 21:31:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/gotz-etl/split-definitions/</guid>
      <description>The definition file job.xml tends to grow as you scrape more and more data sets or pages. This chapter explains how to split the definitions into multiple files for easy maintenance.
Gotz allows you to split the definitions either on job types or on model types.
&amp;nbsp;   (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});  &amp;nbsp; Split on Job Types The examples so far scraped BS, PL, Quote data - price and snapshot - of Acme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split Definitions - Scoopi Web Scraper - CodeTab</title>
      <link>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper-v094/split-definitions-v094/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 04:46:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper-v094/split-definitions-v094/</guid>
      <description>Split Definitions The Scoopi definition file tends to grow as you scrape more and more data sets or pages. This chapter explains how to split the definitions into multiple files for easy maintenance.
Scoopi allows you to split the definitions either on job types or on top level elements.
Split on Job Types The examples so far scraped BS, PL, Quote data - price and snapshot - of Acme. We can split the definitions into three job types quote, bs and pl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split Definitions - Scoopi Web Scraper - why just scrape when you can scoop</title>
      <link>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper/manage/split-definitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 01:18:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.codetab.org/tutorial/scoopi-web-scraper/manage/split-definitions/</guid>
      <description>Split Definitions The Scoopi definition file tends to grow as you scrape multiple types of data or large set of links. This chapter explains how to split the definitions into multiple files for easy maintenance.
Scoopi allows you to split the definitions either on job types or on top level elements.
Split on Job Types The examples so far scraped BS, PL, snapshot data - price and snapshot - of Acme.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>