<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Import Static Site on Codetab</title>
    <link>http://www.codetab.org/tutorial/wordpress/import/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Import Static Site on Codetab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 23:03:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.codetab.org/tutorial/wordpress/import/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Import Static Site - WordPress Tutorial - CodeTab</title>
      <link>http://www.codetab.org/tutorial/wordpress/import/import-static-html-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 01:28:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.codetab.org/tutorial/wordpress/import/import-static-html-site/</guid>
      <description>10.1. WordPress Import Static HTML site In the previous chapters, we saw WordPress installation and optimization. In this chapter, we cover importing Static HTML site and pages as WordPress Posts or Pages and managing dynamic stylesheets of web pages in WordPress.
Sample HTML Files
To import static HTML site or pages, we need to access OpenShift Shell through RHC or PuTTY (for Windows users). OpenShift RHC Client Tools explains RHC and PuTTY setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Child Theme - WordPress Tutorial - CodeTab</title>
      <link>http://www.codetab.org/tutorial/wordpress/import/child-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 04:37:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.codetab.org/tutorial/wordpress/import/child-theme/</guid>
      <description>10.2. WordPress Child Theme In the previous section, we import static HTML files with HTML Import 2 Plugin. The Plugin imports the HTML content and linked images, but it does not import the linked stylesheets and rightly so! In this section, we use WordPress child theme to handle page stylesheets.
WordPress Theme Components Before extending a theme with a child theme, let&amp;rsquo;s understand the structure and components of a WordPress theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Stylesheets - WordPress Tutorial - CodeTab</title>
      <link>http://www.codetab.org/tutorial/wordpress/import/dynamic-stylesheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 05:28:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.codetab.org/tutorial/wordpress/import/dynamic-stylesheets/</guid>
      <description>10.3. WordPress Dynamic Stylesheets In the previous chapter, we understood the structure of a WordPress theme and use it to construct a basic child theme. We also saw the use of the template files in a child theme. In this section - WordPress Dynamic Stylesheets, we explore the child theme further and use it to enable dynamic stylesheets in the WordPress.
Earlier we used HTML Import 2 Plugin to import static HTML pages to WordPress.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>